[
  {
      "question": "1. Oil and water usually collect in compressed air tanks. If you do not have an automatic tank drain, when should you drain the air tanks?",
      "choices": [
          "After every working day.",
          "After every four hours of service.",
          "Once a week."
      ],
      "answer": "After every working day."
  },
  {
      "question": "2. Why should you drain water from the compressed air tanks?",
      "choices": [
          "To keep from fouling the air compressor oil.",
          "Water can freeze in cold weather and cause brake failure.",
          "The low boiling point of water reduces braking power."
      ],
      "answer": "Water can freeze in cold weather and cause brake failure."
  },
  {
      "question": "3. The air brake system for a straight truck or bus should not leak at a rate of more than______ psi per minute with the engine off and the brakes released.",
      "choices": [
          "1",
          "2",
          "3"
      ],
      "answer": "2"
  },
  {
      "question": "4. To make an emergency stop with air brakes, using the stab braking method, you should:",
      "choices": [
          "Pump the brake pedal rapidly and lightly.",
          "Brake hard until the wheels lock, and then get off the brakes for as much time as the wheels were locked.",
          "Press on the brake pedal as hard as you can, release the brakes when the wheels locked, put on the brakes again when the wheels start rolling."
      ],
      "answer": "Press on the brake pedal as hard as you can, release the brakes when the wheels locked, put on the brakes again when the wheels start rolling."
  },
  {
      "question": "5. You should know that your brakes are fading when:",
      "choices": [
          "Pressure on the brake pedal is released and speed increases.",
          "You have to press the brake pedal harder to control speed on a downgrade.",
          "The brake feels spongy when pressure is applied."
      ],
      "answer": "You have to press the brake pedal harder to control speed on a downgrade."
  },
  {
      "question": "6. If the air compressor should develop a leak, what keeps the air in the tanks?",
      "choices": [
          "The tractor protection valve.",
          "The emergency relay valve.",
          "The one-way check valve."
      ],
      "answer": "The one-way check valve."
  },
  {
      "question": "7. To check the brake slack on S-cam brakes, you should park on:",
      "choices": [
          "Park on level ground, chock the wheels, and release the parking brakes.",
          "Stop on level ground and apply the parking brakes.",
          "Park on level ground and drain off air pressure before adjusting."
      ],
      "answer": "Park on level ground, chock the wheels, and release the parking brakes."
  },
  {
      "question": "8. The application pressure gauge shows how much pressure you have:",
      "choices": [
          "In the tanks.",
          "In a modulating control valve.",
          "When you are applying the brakes."
      ],
      "answer": "When you are applying the brakes."
  },
  {
      "question": "9. The spring brakes used on the chambers in a straight truck will bring you to a stop when air pressure drops below:",
      "choices": [
          "60",
          "20",
          "100"
      ],
      "answer": "20"
  },
  {
    "question": "10. The safety valve is set to automatically reduce pressure at:",
    "choices": [
        "150",
        "50",
        "100"
    ],
    "answer": "150"
},
{
    "question": "11. Your truck has a dual air system, and one of the systems loses its pressure. What will happen?",
    "choices": [
        "Brake drums will not be fully pressurized.",
        "Either the front or back brake will not be fully operational.",
        "The manual slack adjusters of the S-cam brakes will not be set properly."
    ],
    "answer": "Either the front or back brake will not be fully operational."
},
{
    "question": "12. If your truck or bus has dual parking control valves, you can use pressure from a separate tank to:",
    "choices": [
        "Balance the service brake system when you are parked.",
        "Release the spring emergency/parking brakes to move a short distance.",
        "Stay parked twice as long without using up service air pressure."
    ],
    "answer": "Release the spring emergency/parking brakes to move a short distance."
},
{
    "question": "13. If your truck has a properly functioning dual air brake system and minimum size air tanks, the air pressure should build from 85 to 100 psi within _ seconds?",
    "choices": [
        "45",
        "60",
        "20"
    ],
    "answer": "45"
},
{
    "question": "14. During normal driving, spring brakes are usually held back by:",
    "choices": [
        "Air Pressure.",
        "Springs.",
        "Bolts and braces."
    ],
    "answer": "Air Pressure."
},
{
    "question": "15. The air compressor stops pumping air at what psi?",
    "choices": [
        "125",
        "100",
        "150"
    ],
    "answer": "125"
},
{
    "question": "16. The driver must be able to see a warning before pressure in the service air tanks falls below _ psi.",
    "choices": [
        "55",
        "50",
        "80"
    ],
    "answer": "55"
},
{
    "question": "17. Excessive use of the service brakes results in overheating, which can lead to:",
    "choices": [
        "Expansion of the brake drums.",
        "Increase contact between the brake drums and linings.",
        "Proper adjustment of S-cam."
    ],
    "answer": "Expansion of the brake drums."
},
{
    "question": "18. The most common type of foundation brake found on heavy vehicles is the:",
    "choices": [
        "Wedge drum.",
        "S-cam drum.",
        "Disc drum."
    ],
    "answer": "S-cam drum."
},{
  "question": "19. If you must make an emergency stop, brake so you:",
  "choices": [
      "Use the hand brake before the brake pedal.",
      "Can steer and your vehicle stays in a straight line.",
      "Use the full power of the brakes to lock them."
  ],
  "answer": "Can steer and your vehicle stays in a straight line."
},
{
  "question": "20. The braking power of the spring brakes:",
  "choices": [
      "Is not affected by the condition of the service brakes.",
      "Increases when the service brakes are hot.",
      "Depends on the service brakes being in adjustment."
  ],
  "answer": "Depends on the service brakes being in adjustment."
},
{
  "question": "21. The air brake lag distance at 55 mph on dry pavement adds about feet.",
  "choices": [
      "32 feet.",
      "45 feet.",
      "65 feet."
  ],
  "answer": "32 feet."
},
{
  "question": "22. Total stopping distance for air brakes is longer than that for hydraulic brakes due to distance.",
  "choices": [
      "Brake lag.",
      "Reaction distance.",
      "Effective braking."
  ],
  "answer": "Brake lag."
},
{
  "question": "23. It is accepted that too much heat caused by using your brakes too often can also cause:",
  "choices": [
      "Modulated control valve to wear out.",
      "Brake linings to split up.",
      "Brake fade or failure."
  ],
  "answer": "Brake fade or failure."
},
{
  "question": "24. Repeatedly pressing and releasing (fanning) the brake pedal may result in:",
  "choices": [
      "The loss of brake air pressure.",
      "A build up of brake air pressure.",
      "No change of brake air pressure."
  ],
  "answer": "The loss of brake air pressure."
},
{
  "question": "25. The brake system that applies and releases the brakes when the driver uses the brake pedal is the______ brake system.",
  "choices": [
      "Emergency.",
      "Service.",
      "Parking."
  ],
  "answer": "Service."
},
{
  "question": "26. A slack adjuster's free play needs to be adjusted if it is more than about _______ how many inches when you pull hard on it?",
  "choices": [
      "1/4 inch",
      "1/2 inch",
      "1 inch"
  ],
  "answer": "1 inch"
},
{
  "question": "27. An air brake system is fully charged at what psi?",
  "choices": [
      "125",
      "150",
      "75"
  ],
  "answer": "125"
},
{
  "question": "28. The brake pedal in an air brake system:",
  "choices": [
      "Control the speed of the air compressor.",
      "Controls the air pressure applied to put on the brakes.",
      "Is connected to slack adjusters by a series of rods and linkages."
  ],
  "answer": "Controls the air pressure applied to put on the brakes."
},{
  "question": "29. The S-cam:",
  "choices": [
      "Controls the flow air to each of the brake chambers.",
      "Pulls the brake shoes away from the drum and allow the wheels to roll freely.",
      "Forces the brake shoes against the inside of the brake drum."
  ],
  "answer": "Forces the brake shoes against the inside of the brake drum."
},
{
  "question": "30. Under normal conditions in order to engage the parking brakes the driver must first:",
  "choices": [
      "Turn off the engine.",
      "Let the air out of the spring brakes.",
      "Be sure air brakes system is fully pressurized."
  ],
  "answer": "Let the air out of the spring brakes."
},
{
  "question": "31. Which of these is NOT a proper time to apply the parking brakes?",
  "choices": [
      "If your brakes are very hot.",
      "To use parking brakes if you park for less than 1 hour.",
      "If you are going to use the parking brakes you need to make sure that they will hold the vehicle."
  ],
  "answer": "If your brakes are very hot."
},
{
  "question": "32. If the spring brakes are on, when should you push the brake pedal?",
  "choices": [
      "Only when driving downhill.",
      "Only on the slippery road.",
      "Never."
  ],
  "answer": "Never."
},
{
  "question": "33. What is the first thing you should do when a low air pressure warning comes on:",
  "choices": [
      "Upshift.",
      "Downshift.",
      "Stop and safely park as soon as possible."
  ],
  "answer": "Stop and safely park as soon as possible."
},
{
  "question": "34. The parking or emergency brake on a heavy vehicle can only be held in position by something that cannot leak away, like:",
  "choices": [
      "Spring pressure.",
      "Air pressure.",
      "Hydraulic pressure."
  ],
  "answer": "Spring pressure."
},
{
  "question": "35. Air braking takes more time than hydraulic braking because air:",
  "choices": [
      "Takes more time to flow through the lines than hydraulic fluid.",
      "Air brakes use different brake drums.",
      "Brakes require heavier return springs."
  ],
  "answer": "Takes more time to flow through the lines than hydraulic fluid."
},
{
  "question": "36. When you apply the brakes, the brake shoes/linings are pressed against the:",
  "choices": [
      "Brake drum.",
      "Slack adjuster.",
      "S-cam."
  ],
  "answer": "Brake drum."
},
{
  "question": "37. If air pressure is NOT build up fast enough within the correct amount of time:",
  "choices": [
      "You should be ready to use your parking brakes to stop.",
      "The alcohol container may be low.",
      "You air pressure may drop too low during driving."
  ],
  "answer": "You air pressure may drop too low during driving."
},
{
  "question": "38. The proper method of braking when going down a long and/or steep grades after selecting the proper gear, is to brake until your speed is about _ miles per hour below your 'safe' speed, then release your brakes.",
  "choices": [
      "5",
      "10",
      "15"
  ],
  "answer": "5"
}
]
